ERNEST POUGH

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

CONTACT DETAILS



ERNESTPOUGH.DEV



/POUGHE



in /ERNESTPOUGH



POUGHE@GMAIL.COM

SUMMARY

Focused and quick-learning Software Engineer with over ten years of United States Army Reserve experience in a variety of technical roles in engineering and electronics. I am looking to join a team building projects for a mission driven

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- CSS3/HTML5
- JavaScript
- Node.js
- **Express**
- MongoDB
- **SEO** Optimization
- DNS Setting
- Web Hosting
- Responsive Web Development
- Browser Developer Tools
- Git/GitHub
- Java

MILITARY SKILLS

- Familiar with frequently used IC/Government databases and tools
- Read and understand electrical schematics, wiring diagrams, panels, and meters
- U.S. Army Power Generation (91D) Course
- U.S. Army HUMINT (35M) Course
- CPR/First-Aid

EDUCATION

Northern Virginia Community College

Computer Science/General Studies (Double | JAN 2020 - Present

- -CGPA: 3.7
- -Dean's List Student
- -Officer in campus Coding Club
- -Phi Theta Kappa Honor Society
- -NSLS Honor Society

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

RESILIENT CODERS | JUL 2021-Present

- Maintained detailed git history for all projects used GitHub in a team environment
- Created various logo designs and multiple page layouts
- Adapted quickly to project outcomes
- Maintained detailed git history for all projects and used GitHub in a team environment

Recent Projects:

- We Care FullStack Application A web platform connecting youth that share interests in those professions.
- Petstagram FullStack Application A social media application that allows users to share their favorite pictures of pets.
 Gardner-Grounds FullStack Application Local coffee shop web
- <u>Casino Roulette</u> FullStack Application The classic Roulette casino

Software Engineer

FREELANCE | AUG 2021 - Present

· Creating full stack applications and websites for different clients across small and medium

Recent Projects:

• Finesse Automotive Works Website: A fully custom website for a local automotive body shop

Tactical Power Generation Specialist

US ARMY RESERVES | DEC 2010 - Present

- Deployment 2020: In support of Covid-19 Pandemic Relief Efforts
- Leads and trains teams of up to 45 soldiers in both classroom and practical application settings on HUMINT, power generation and basic soldier functions.
- Leads groups up to 20 in size to accomplish various missions ranging from detainee operations to organizing inventory for a battalion sized element

Operations Supervisor

REPUBLIC SERVICES | AUG 2019 - NOV 2019

• Monitored and audited compressed natural gas vehicles, maintained 100% accountability of \$20M in company assets

Field Transportation Specialist

AMAZON | MAY 2017 - APR 2019